Inventory of the J.E. Morpurgo Papers 1937-2000
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Miscellaneous Non-J.E.M., n.d., 1940-1970. (Box-folder 11:21-30)
  - Dianne Per-Lee, Folklore and the Nationalistic Spirit: A Short Story of the Influence of Nationalism on American Folklore, 24 August 1970., 1 item. (Box-folder 11:29)
    A paper written for class on "America and Europe" taught by J.E.M.
  - Miscellaneous, Various dates. (Box-folder 11:30)
    Items of uncertain origin-unmatched pages and fragments.
  Series 18: Photographs
- Photographs, n.d., 1936-1963, 1993., 18 photographs. (Box-folder 11:31)
  - Photograph of J.E.M.: Jack as a Grecian, 1936., 2 items, Black and white, Original, 5X31/2 (P1); enlargement, 7X4(P2). (Box-folder 11:31)
  - Photographs of J.E.M. in William and Mary theater production of First Lady, 1937., 2 items, black and white, 8X10, (P3, P4). (Box-folder 11:31)
  - J.E.M. with Sheikh Mohammed Younnis Said Abdulla El Said Wahid Rais Tel Afar, in Tel Afar, Iraq, 1941., 1 item, black and white (P5). (Box-folder 11:31)
  - Photograph of the Penguin and Pelican editorial meeting at the Bureau of Current Affairs, 117 Piccadilly, 1946., 1 item (P6). (Box-folder 11:31)
    Left to right: Tanya Kent, Jack Morpurgo, Richard Lane, Allen Lane, Bill Williams, Eunice Frost, Alan Glover.
  - Photograph of the UNESCO seminar in Rangoon, 1957., 1 item (P7). (Box-folder 11:31)
  - Photograph of J.E.M. and Prince Philip of Edinburgh, 1964., 2 items, black and white, 8X6 (P8, P9). (Box-folder 11:31)
  - Photograph of J.E.M. and Queen Elizabeth of England, 1964., 1 item, black and white, 8X6 (P10). (Box-folder 11:31)
  - Photograph of J.E.M. with Mr. Baker and Dr. Freiherr von Brand, 1966., 1 item, black and white, 5X7 (P11). (Box-folder 11:31)
  - Photo of J.E.M. on stairs at the National Book League, n.d., 1 item, black and white, 111/2X61/2 (P12). (Box-folder 11:31)
  - Slide of J.E.M. with books, n.d., 1 item, color (P13). (Box-folder 11:31)
  - J.E.M with Lord Eccles, n.d., 1 item, black and white, 8X6 (P14). (Box-folder 11:31)
  - Photograph of the honorary degree ceremony at William and Mary, [1970?]., 2 items, color, 8X10 (P15, P16). (Box-folder 11:31)
  - J.E.M. at an academic ceremony with Aaron Copland, Edward Boyle, and Charles Heston, n.d., 1 item, color, 41/2X41/2 (P17). (Box-folder 11:31)
  - Group photograph from William and Mary class of 1938 reunion, n.d., 1 item, color, 8X12 (P18). (Box-folder 11:31)
    People shown the photo include: J.E.M., Helen Wood Walker, Frances Jenkins Taylor, Virginia Betts Chapman, Anna Roper Bruechert, Jane Speakman Hauge, Bert Sheeran, C.R. Mirmelstein, Doris Froehner, Charlotte Johnson Able, Ella Manning, Elizabeth R. Weber, Frances Schaaf Shepherd, Sally Robbins Carmalt, Bill Anderson, Margaret Brett Honn, Martha "Pete" Moreland Thomas, Mollie Waters Christie, Bob Sheeran, E. Thomas Crowston, and William A. Reynolds.
  Series 19: Artifacts, prints, awards
- Artifacts, prints, awards, n.d., 1938, 1981. (Box 12-16)
  - Bodleian plate, n.d., 1 item, 141/2 X18 (A1). (Box 12)
    Framed reproduction.
  - Bruton Parish, n.d., 1 item, 141/2X18 (A2). (Box 12)
    Framed color print.
  - Capitol building, n.d, 1 item, 141/2X18 (A3). (Box 12)
  - Josiah Chowning quote and illustration, n.d., 1 item, 91/2X5 (A4). (Box 12)
  - Governor's Palace, n.d., 1 item, 91/2X5 (A4). (Box 12)
  - Document relating to King's Arms Tavern, n.d., 1 item, 10X6 (A6). (Box 12)
  - Rules of Behaviour, 1787: Children's Behaviour at the Meeting House, n.d., 1 item, 13X10 (A7). (Box 13)
  - Rules of Behaviour, 1787: Children's Behaviour at table, n.d., 1 item, 13X10 (A8). (Box 13)
    Framed.
  - Wren building, n.d., 1 item, 141/2X 18 (A9). (Box 13)
  - Wren building, n.d., 1 item, 13X18 (A10). (Box 13)
    Framed drawing.
  - Debate Trophy from William and Mary, 1938., 1 item (A 12). (Box 14)
  - Plaque of William and Mary seal, n.d., 1 item (A11). (Box 15)
  - Plaque given to J.E.M. for his talk, Richer in Esteem: A Re-Appraisal of Gentleman Johnny Burgoyne, 6 October 1981., 1 item. (Box 16)
  Series 20: Audio materials
- Audio materials, n.d., 1975. (Box 17)
  - Interview with Richard Lane, May 1975., 1 audio cassette tape (AV3a). (Box 17)
  - Interview with Allen Lane, n.d., 4 audio cassettes tapes (AV3b-e).
  - Recordings of the William and Mary choir under the direction of Carl A. Fehr, n.d., 3 records (record number 3 is missing) (AV3). (Box 17)
  Series 21: Library
- Library, n.d., 1908-2000. (Box 17 and general library collection)
    Subseries 21.2: Magazines and journals
  - Magazines and journals, 1985-2000., 34 items. (Box 17)
    - The Charles Lamb Bulletin, July 1985-April 1993., 29 issues. (Box 17)
    - Colonial Williamsburg Magazine, 1999-2000., 4 issues. (Box 17)
      Issues included: June/July 1999, Aug. Sept. 1999, October/November 1999 and Spring 2000.
    - William and Mary Alumni Society, Spring 2000., 1 item. (Box 17)
    Subseries 21.2: Books
  - n.d., 1908-1995. (Box General library collection)
    The books of J.E.M.'s personal library have been transferred to Swem Library's general collection. The titels of all books originally included in this collection are listed below (see LION catalog for call numbers).
    - Allan, G.A.T., Christ's Hospital, London: Blackie and Son Limited, 1937., 1 item.
    - Allan, G.A.T., Christ's Hospital, London: Town and Country Books, 1984., 1 item.
      Revised by J.E. Morpurgo.
    - Andrews, Matthew Page, Virginia: The Old Dominion, Garden City: Doubleday, Doran and Company, Inc., 1937., 1 item.
    - Blunden, Edmund. Christ's Hospital: A Retrospect, London: Christophers, n.d., 1 item.
    - British Historical Portraits: A Selection from the National Portrait Gallery with Biographical Notes, Cambridge: Published for the National Portrait Gallery at the University Press, 1957., 1 item.
    - Christ's Hospital Admissions, Harrison and Sons, Ltd., 1937., 1 item.
      Vol. 1, 1554-1599.
    - The Christ's Hospital Book, London: Hamish Hamilton, 1953., 1 item.
    - Christ's Hospital Club: Officers, Past Presidents and Roll of Members, Christ's Hospital Enterprises Ltd., December 1994., 1 item.
    - Coldham, Peter Wilson, Child Apprentices in America from Christ's Hospital, London, 1617-1778, Surrey, England: Genealogical Publishing Co., Inc., 1990., 1 item.
      N.B. Marginalia by J.E.M.?
    - College of William and Mary list of alumni, 1693-1888, n.d., 1 item.
    - Earle, Peter, Sailors: English Merchant Seamen 1650-1775, London: Methuen, 1998., 1 item.
    - Epitaphs of Gloucester and Mathews Counties in Tidewater Virginia Through 1865, Richmond: The Virginia State Library, 1959., 1 item.
      Collected by the Association for the Preservation of Virginia Antiquities, Joseph Bryan Branch, Gloucester.
    - Kellaway, William, The New England Company 1649-1776: Missionary Society to the American Indians, London: Longmans, 1961., 1 item.
    - Lempriere, William, A History of the Girls' School of Christ's Hospital London, Hoddesdon and Hertford, Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1924., 1 item.
    - Manzione, Carol Kazmierczak, Christ's Hospital of London, 1552-1598: A Passing Deed of Pity, Selinsgrove: Susquehanna University Press, 1995., 1 item.
    - Meade, Bishop, Old Churches, Ministers and Families of Virginia, Philadelphia: J.B. Lippincott Company, n.d., 2 items.
      Vol. 1-2.
    - Page, Frances M., Christ's Hospital Hertford: A History of the School Against the Background of London and Horsham, London: G. Bell and Sons, Ltd., 1953., 1 item.
    - Pearce, E.H., Annals of Christ's Hospital, London: Hugh Rees, Ltd., 1908., 1 item.
    - Roberts, H.A., The Records of the Amicable Society of Blues and Its Predecessors from 1629 to 1895, Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1924., 1 item.
    - Starkey, Marion L., The Devil in Massachusetts: A Modern Inquiry into the Salem Witch Trials, London: Robert Hale Limited, n.d., 1 item.
    - Smith, Abbot Emerson, Colonists in Bondage: White Servitude and Convict Labor in America,1607-1776, Chapel Hill: University of North Carolina Press, 1947, 1 item.